Carlini8: There wasn't any
opportunity like there is now
where you can take Ethereum, do
stuff with it and have more
Ethereum. That's generally what
people in the NFT space are
doing. They're trying to make
ETH. Most tokens aren't launched
legally. And I think that will
be a big problem for projects as
well. Because, like I've said
earlier, the team is the
important bit, you know, pretty
much the outside image of your
NFT project right now is all
about Twitter. And this is just
a very powerful way to get your
community interacting more on
Twitter. Every community with
this would interact more.
Valerio: What's up everyone?
Welcome to a another show
another episode on the
Talkenized Show. I'm your host,
Valerio. I'm here with Konrad.
What's up? Konrad?
Konrad: Hi, hello.
Valerio: And I'm very happy for
today's episode, because today's
guest is a OG. He's been into
the NFT space since four years
now since 2017. And he's the
founder of the Purrnelope's
Country Club. What's up, James?
What's up Carlini? Thank you so
much for taking the time and
joining us today.
Carlini8: All right. Thanks for
having me on.
Konrad: I'm super, super happy
to have you, man and to talk
about your background and about
your current project and about
your general view on web three.
So to get started, Carlini, can
you give us a short introduction
for anyone who doesn't know you
yet? Well? Who are you and what
you do right now?
Carlini8: Yeah, sure. So Carlini
8. I've been in NFTs since 2017.
crypto. I'm not actually sure,
because I mined very briefly
some bitcoin. And all I know is
I did it in my old house, which
I lived in 2013 2015. And that's
a few that had drovers a few
weeks ago. And I kind of got
trolled out of mining Bitcoin,
because I was told, Oh, you're,
you're a millionaire. Yeah. And
then I checked, like, overnight,
I'd mined 4 P worth of bitcoin
at the time or something like
that. Four pence, probably about
six cents.
Konrad: You mined six cents
worth of bitcoin,
Carlini8: overnight, like every
night, I guess So I, I used my
gaming PC to mine. And it was
when I wasn't using it, you
know, it's just like idly mining
overnight. And it was not very
powerful. So it didn't do much,
but it was probably at the time
costing me costing me money and
electricity. But that that hard
drive was wiped many times and
it wouldn't have been much. And
then 2015 is where my smaller
purchases started happening in
crypto. And I was mainly when I
when I started getting bigger
buyers, I was mainly interested
in ETH just because I like that
you can do stuff like you know,
bitcoins great for starting all
of this and for what it
represents and what it can do.
monetarily, but that that didn't
really interest me and never
brought me in it was more the
the utility I guess of Ethereum.
They're just hooked me in and
full, full blown degens since
2017, pretty much
Konrad: all right. So so what
what are you doing at the
moment?
Carlini8: So currently I run
Purrnelope's Country Club. It's
a 10k PFP NFT projects. But
we're just trying to I guess do
it right. So I've been in NFTs.
Pretty much since you know, they
weren't mainstream. There are a
couple couple projects before I
came in, but certainly not many
people. So I've seen how NFTs
have changed and where we expect
them to go. And back in 2017. We
had where we expected them to
go. And we've sort of seen how
we've progressed towards that.
And I just want to sort of
utilize the technology with a
project as best as possible,
which I guess are our main
current utility we have that
shows that our Fiza ens
subdomains where each cat is
able to claim a dot PCC dot ETH
domain for free, which is just
like an ens domain instead of
dot ETH. You get .pcc.eth But
it's also free because you get
it from us who have paid for it
PCC dot ETH. And that becomes
your wallet. And it can be it
can turn your username into a
profile picture. And just even
little things like I can't
search for all of the users on
Twitter who have a Purrnelope's
as Country Club profile picture.
But I can search .pcc.eth go
click on people, and it shows me
everyone that has that in their
name. So it's, we we've actually
got something coming that sort
of links that to discord as
well. And that will just be
showing even more. So how this,
this can be pushed, because
you've effectively got your
digital identity linked over
Ethereum, Twitter and discord.
And we can do lots of things.
Once that's all linked up. Yep.
Konrad: And can you link your
NFT to any social media profile
like Facebook, Instagram, and so
on, or limited by something?
Carlini8: When I say linked,
it's bad centralized, I guess.
So that's not on Ethereum. And
that's with a bot, were able to
search using the Twitter API,
they just got API, and then
Ethereum to check the subdomain.
So for what we're planning to
do, you could you could probably
do the same for Instagram and
Facebook, but it would just be
integrating with their APIs.
Konrad: All right. Makes sense.
All right. When did you guys
start with with PCC with the
project?
Carlini8: We started building it
towards the end of March last
year. So we started over a year
ago now, but we mint. I think we
started minted in June.
Konrad: All right, how did the
launch go? How to demand go.
Carlini8: It was slow, because
at the time, we were completely
anonymous. Because I was working
for NFT boxes before it started
NFT boxes were my co founder
Pranksy December 2020. And I
ended up in March selling my
half of NFT boxes to him. But
that was there was lots of sort
of legal loopholes, we had to
jump through and all these sort
of things. So ended up taking
maybe four months to sort that
out. And I didn't think it was
the right two people at the time
for what I was working on NFT
boxes, we couldn't tell them why
I wasn't or that I wasn't. So it
didn't seem right that we were
like, Hey, I'm launching this as
well. So we're anonymous until
the sale was confirmed. And as
soon as the NFT boxes sale was
confirmed. We unanoned as a team
said, Hey, this is us. We sold
out in a couple of hours.
Konrad: And how did you
initially come up with an idea
of PCC? Was it your own idea? Or
did you have a team because it.
Carlini8: So we are a team of
three of us at the start. One
who had come from Box NFT boxes
with me, the community manager
who was part time but wanted
sort of a full time stable job
because this was I guess, not
bang in the middle of lockdowns
and COVID. But they were sort of
coming back it was January to
March 2021, you know, a bit
unstable and just wanted to be
locked down in in a solid job.
So that wasn't something I could
offer NFT boxes, someone else
who I was going to bring over to
NFT boxes is to sort of sort
that side of things out as well,
who I got to quit a job brought
him with me. So that's 3.
And we originally had a couple
of ideas on what we wanted to do
was take my side of NFT boxes, I
worked with the community and
sort of made made the things
work, I guess, like the website
and the contracts, I'd find the
right people for that. And we
wanted to make sure it's
community focused. And our
original idea was sort of to try
and help creators. Like you guys
have a podcast, we would come in
with some sort of NFT rewards
that would kind of build in
Patreon or Twitch subscriptions.
You know how to Twitch their
badges after six months in a
year and two and three years.
Why aren't they NFTs? So we're
gonna go down that line. And I
told these two guys, like, I'll
fund it for a year and we'll see
where we are Ah, and we were
sort of going down that route.
And then someone said, How are
we going to make money? So I
don't know. Hopefully find it.
If he said, at the end of the
year, what happens? Do I have to
find a job, I don't believe
properly unless you know, we've
got VC funding or get bought out
or something like that. And he's
like, I want to make money. I
want, I want this to be a job.
And by I want to make money,
that's more I want that to be a
salary for me. So we just
looked, you know, the matter at
the time was 10k, PFP. And then
we sort of amended our plans
like, right, how can we take the
10k PFP and push that towards
community and sort of, in effect
doing it right. And you can see
sort of on chain, how we've
spent the Ethereum from the
original sale, most of which
went into a kitty vault now
worth over 1000 Ethereum, which
is 200 ETH of more than our
wholesale. So we've sort of
created this community pot
that's bigger than all of the
money we've taken in, which sort
of just shows it's not a meant
and make us rich, it's a meant
and build for the community.
Konrad: All right. They
understand. Previously, you
mentioned your launch, right.
Your initial launch was in May
last year, right.
Carlini8: I'm kind of guessing.
I was a couple of seconds. And
go to a call. It was 269 days
ago.
Konrad: Wow. Almost a year.
Right?
Carlini8: Almost 269 days ago,
please help me get it was 17 for
July
Valerio: 25. July. Alright.
Oh, quickly. Did you sell out?
Carlini8: It took about a month,
I'd say. So it was just very
slowly minting until I was able
to because I was originally
Topcat Topcat was running the
project. And then as soon as
Carlini eight was running the
project, it minted it out in a
few hours. Think it was about a
month between those times.
Konrad: All right. What do you
mean by running the project?
What did you do differently than
than top cat?
Carlini8: I was just called top
cat. I couldn't be me. I
couldn't
Valerio: think of all the
anonymity and the public name, I
guess. All right.
Carlini8: So people knew they
weren't going to get well. They
don't know that I'm going to get
wrote quite a high chance that
you know, my my main wallet has
16,000 transactions. It's been
there 1400 days or something
like that. And not once in that
time have I scammed anyone. So
at that point, you know,
interesting. quite confident.
Konrad: How many pieces Did you
sell before you announced that
you are you?
Carlini8: Maybe 2000?
Konrad: Okay, because my
question is that at that time,
there were a lot of profile pic
projects where a lot of them had
anonymous team and how did you
manage the community to like
stay organized because I've been
on many discourage during the
time and if a project didn't
sell out in like a day or two
people were just panicking all
over the place and claim it as a
total scam.
Carlini8: I think I think how
that plays out is generally how
do you get a get the community
in the first place? So like,
like I said, we were trying to
do it right. So we weren't
paying people to promote us
weren't paying for tweets. We
weren't, you know, sneakily,
underhand, well, maybe not even
underhand, but given these alpha
groups, you know, couple of ETH
like, Hey, you start minting you
start minting we'll give you
this ETH that ETH you'll get
everything half price or
whatever. They start minting
sets off some alerts other
people start minting some
projects, even their own, their
own NFT is you know, they just
get a few 100 ETH mint a few
1000 yourself sets off the
alerts yourself. Away you go.
You're just giving yourself
money effectively at that point
with a little bit of gas fees.
Oh, well. So we were just
totally you know, I guess
upfront, not paying for hype.
And I've seen quite a lot of
people trying to do it you know,
that way and struggle if you
don't follow the matter of the
time. You will you will find it
hard in this space because there
are some excellent marketers
They've come into this space.
And the problem is that's really
where their talents lie. Maybe
one or two people on the team
are just really good at creating
the hype and marketing. But then
there's no one to execute once
is minted. And we're just seeing
so many so many projects, I
think a couple of months ago, I
looked back at a certain day,
last year, I think it was the
day it was it was a year before.
And there were these calendar
projects that used to just put
out here, today's mints, and I
just looked at every project,
and two was still active. Ish.
One, I kind of ignored art
blocks because there was an art
block summit that day. And in
reality, that's just art and art
blocks is a platform. But
everything else there was was
maybe nine or 10 projects that
hadn't tweeted this year, there
was no discord activity, maybe
half of them their websites were
deleted. But the one the one
year, the one year renewal of
their website hadn't been
continued.
Konrad: Alright. So what makes
it project being like long term
because I would say that if
you're running it for a year
now, we can call the success
because as you said, like you've
seen many projects starting the
same day and just dying out. So
how do you survive for this
market, which is, I wouldn't say
saturated, but there are a lot
of new projects coming in every
day. And there's huge noise in
the space.
Carlini8: It's it is the team,
at the end of the day, because
if the team keep building, that
project is still alive, the may
not be many holders, the floor
may be basically zero. But when
they can tweet, something, like
we've been here, two years
building, we've done this, that
and the other, the the only
problems can come down to their
funding, if if they just you
know, end up having to, if they
just gotta go get a job, because
this, this project isn't paying
them or whatever. But as long as
the team are going to stay
around the there's always a
chance, right? So the projects
where the teams leave, they're
done. They like they just can't
be revived. There's no reason I
know, there are NFTs and anyone
can spin up a site and build a
game around that NFT that
they've said that says the
crypto kitties days, it was like
build, they even back then they
tried to pay people to build on
top of crypto kitties, very
small amounts compared to now
because you know, the money
involved in crypto was so much
lower than but they, it just, it
just never works. Because why
would anyone put in a lot of
effort for someone else's
product, when if they're going
to build something, they could
just sell their own their own
avatars, or land or whatever it
is that works within the game
card games. And it's just very
tricky to make that work. So
really, the lifeblood of every
NFT project is running like a
business. Because the will of
course, be art, you know,
artists aren't expected to do,
you know, make a game or
anything like that. They just
keep creating art. And it's very
much its own category. But I'm
talking about the projects that
should be run as a company. If
the team keep going, they can
always build a community around
it, it's it's harder. It's
always easiest at mint because
you get in, you build up that
height because Mint is coming.
But the the rugs will be when
when a team member leaves when
the team leaves, it's it's just
done at this at this period of
time, maybe, you know, maybe in
five years time, maybe even
less, we'll see we'll see time
where a community really has
built up around a project. And
they can survive without a team.
All right, but we're not there
yet.
Konrad: And even if the team
like comes back, like a couple
of weeks after because that's
what what we're seeing with some
of the projects that are not
started like this year 2022 that
the team is gone. And then like
a month later, like the founders
is saying on Twitter. Hello
guys. I'm back. Let's do it
again. But I guess it's not the
same anymore. Right.
Carlini8: And I'm sure that
definitely has nothing to do
with the guys who have gone to
prison for a few years for
effectively just straight
rocking. So oh, if we if we
quickly go back now maybe they
won't think we wrote them and we
were just incompetent.
Konrad: It's true that he
announced his comeback like a
couple of days afterwards. Yeah,
it was fun. Um But what exactly
do you mean by, you know,
keeping a project life? What do
you mean by by building? How do
you do keep the project alive?
That's the main question do you
focus on, on providing value in
some way providing utility on a
on a long term basis constantly?
Or how do you keep a project
alive?
And all that sort of thing,
because usually, when you start
a project you've had you have
the vision, and the direction
you want to go into. And you can
call the donor Combinator, like
milestones. So if you accomplish
them, how do you come up with
new ideas that you want to
execute?
Carlini8: Well in for new goals
in this space, normally, it's
just, you know, spend 1819 hours
a day on Twitter. And then as
soon as some cool new stuff
happens, you see it and you're
like, right, how can I? Can we
use that? Can we improve that.
So even even just recently, OWL
from cyberkongz, the Dev has
released a guardian contract,
which is effectively unchained
two factor authentification, you
can set it up so that you can
have your NFT in a hot wallet.
But you can only move it or do
certain things with it. If you
then sign a transaction from a
different hardware wallet, which
means you can use it in a game.
But you can't be scammed out of
that NFT, unless you go to your
hardware wallet that you've
locked away. And you you know,
you put somewhere far enough
away that while you're walking
to it, you think should I really
be doing this is this person
really not stealing my ape. So
you just got to be ready for
whatever that new next thing is.
I think NFT worlds have changed
that as well. Just because
they're building effectively on
the most played game in history,
Minecraft, they're sort of the
underlying layer. But the battle
hardened code that's underneath
it, they've added their own
token, and they're allowing
communities to come around a
game effectively, the game that
has to be built by the devs. So
that's another angle lots of
projects. Now we're building a
game in NFT worlds are all of
these different sort of ones
that are building up. But in it,
the I guess the answer is always
different for different
projects, because they will all
have their own little different
goals. And for us, it's to use
that NFT to the best of its
ability. So I do think the ens
thing that I'd mentioned
earlier, I think that's one of
the greatest NFT utilities at
the moment. And it is kind of
confusing to me why everyone
isn't copying us. I would just
expect people to see it. I know
we're quite small, like not
diluted that you know, we're one
of the projects that people will
be keeping eyes on all the time.
But it it should have, I feel
like he should have twigged in a
couple of founders minds maybe
it's just not high on their
priority list and it's on their
to do list or whatever. But
really, whatever the project is
building to so if you're if it's
a story we've seen with cyber
brokers, they've had missions
over the past week every day,
and that's built up to a reward
which I think is a mecca arm but
that's clearly then building to
something so there's some kind
of story going on their bored
apes are coming out with their
land azuki did their in real
life. Check your wallets drop.
doodles going down the non
dilutive, non dilutive, get
everyone in somehow route which
is going to be very interesting
to see how they do that. So it's
just all these projects coming
up with their own ways to bring
value to their community. And
when there's a winner, I think
we'll see a lot of people
following
Konrad: all right, what by the
way, what what do you think is
the biggest advantage of holding
a .pcc.eth domain like what what
makes you so so confident that
you're wondering yourself why
other founders haven't?
Carlini8: It's it's not
.pcc.eeth. It's dot anything dot
Eve. So I'm not saying dot PCC
dot ETH is the greatest thing
ever. I'm saying the concept
itself is great. For example, we
see we see new ba YC new azuki
with founders Every day, they're
all verified. They're all
tagging us on Twitter. If their
username was.ba yc.eth
something.ba, YC dot eth. That
would be unchained verification
that they're real. It's a bit
like the hexagon on Twitter. But
it's a username. So it would, it
will cut out that sort of
scamming. And you don't need to
ask them for their wallet. So if
you're doing a deal with someone
that's pretending to be whatever
dot bayc dot eth, and they say,
oh, actually send it to this
other wallet, that should set
off alarm bells, because they've
publicly said this is their
wallet. Why are they wanting to
send this somewhere else? It's
clearly a scam. And it's, it's
just the other integration as
well. So we were going to be
able to give people a slight
nudge to use dot PCC dot ETH on
Discord and Twitter. And that
itself is powerful marketing.
For a project like us, it would
be even bigger for a bigger
project, if suddenly you have
like, there's no doubt in my
mind that if bored apes did it
before 1000 people on Twitter
with Dot BaYC, dot Eth, within a
week. And just seeing those all
over Twitter, the ability to
search, eight, follow eight
would be so much stronger. And
right now, NFTs are marketing
really, when we when we get down
to it.
Konrad: But why would I not be
able to just change my username,
for example, also to dot, I
don't know to Valerio dot baYC
dot eth
Carlini8: like that won't work.
Konrad: But for Twitter, to
change your username, you don't
need to link it to your wallet,
right? It's only for the hexagon
profile.
Carlini8: I'm fully expecting
some form down the line with
Twitter a verification. So you
know how they've recently added
the links with the little blue
ticks. If they're a real link,
they verify that links aren't a
scam. Alright.
Konrad: I'm not sure if I knew a
bit about this,
Carlini8: it's pretty new a few
days, I've just got Twitter
open. So I'll just send you I
haven't seen as well in the
discord. Just next to links,
there's a green circle with a
white ticket. And I fully expect
they are able to verify that an
NFT you own an NFT. And it
shouldn't be too much of a leap
for them to be able to verify
that you own a subdomain. So I
think very quickly that will
become a searchable proof of
ownership because you can only
have that if you own for us you
can only have dot PCC dot ETH if
you own a Purrnelope, and you
cannot fake like with an NFT.
You can you can just mentor
bored ape and get a hexagon. You
can you know you can just mentor
on open see just a picture of it
is obviously fake. But Twitter
will verify exists an NFT.
Whereas we've got PCC dot ETH
you cannot verify that the only
way to verify it is by actually
having it. So when that when
their version of a hexagon be
that a tick or I don't know,
colorful semi circle around it
or something like that. That
will be sort of the gold
standard of not getting scammed,
I think.
Konrad: All right, interesting.
So So basically, you think that
in some time that it's possible
to change your username, I mean,
similar to the profile pic,
right? Where you connect to your
wallet, and then obviously the
domain. I mean, it's everything
on chain, right? So it's easy to
prove, and verify if you
actually own it. And then you're
actually able to change your
user name to whatever if you own
whatever domain you own, similar
to the profile pic. Alright.
Carlini8: And that's sort of
short term thinking as well. If
you go, you know, long term, pie
in the sky, which often people
talk about when thinking about
NF. TS, you know, logging into
your email with your subdomain,
your your web free version of
email, whatever that is logging
into Facebook, Instagram, even
Twitter itself. This could be
done via your wallet. And your
wallet is your subdomain. It's
snow. It's how your wallet is
represented, I guess. But you
will be logging in as this. This
subdomain for everything in the
long term.
Konrad: i It's very interesting
because I was always asking
myself I could just as you said
earlier, I could use CTRL S like
a bored eight, right? Safe,
safety picture and just just
meant it. And then I own the
NFT. It's not the official one,
but I still own on the NFT and
can upload it to as a hexagon on
Twitter. And on the first site,
it's a bored ape. Right? And I
don't think all people, I don't
think everyone actually clicks
on it, and then scrolls down and
checks if all right, it's the
official collection and stuff.
Usually, it's just the first for
sidebar people are
Carlini8: never I've never
checked a hexagon, ever. I've
never, I didn't even know you
didn't know you could. So now
I'm having to scroll. And yeah,
Konrad: I did a couple of times,
but I don't think I'm I think
I'm the minority. But yeah. I
mean, most people are lazy, so
so that they will just see the
bored ape. And they're like,
alright, it's official one. But
but that's super, super cool,
actually. And I've never thought
about that. Well. So I guess
we'll see it. Soon that other
projects start implemented
something like this,
Carlini8: we were already kind
of alpha, I guess we're already
confirming real Twitter
Usernames, we have a bot coming.
haven't actually no one in the
community knows. So this is, you
know, fresh info for them. But
there's a bot coming that will
check discord, check Twitter,
and check the subdomains
registered. And if they all
match, you will be able to get a
role in the discord. And also,
there'll be a leaderboard that
shows how many of these verified
people you follow. So in a way,
you're pushing, you know, ape
follow ape, there's no way
there's no reason to put that
tweet out. Because we literally
have this leaderboard, showing
who we're incentivizing people
to go and follow the rest of the
community. And that just, you
know, pretty much the outside
image of your NFT project right
now is all about Twitter. And
this is just a very powerful way
to get your community
interacting more on Twitter,
every community with this would
interact more. So our
percentage, you know, might be
quite small, and we're starting
from a small place. But again,
as a concept, if doodles did
this, how, how much would that
explain the community? You know,
these sorts of things?
Konrad: Interesting. Yeah. I
don't know if you have anything
to add here, but do you
know, no, I just wanted to move
to another topic. If we're long
with it.
I would like to talk a little
bit about the background first.
Valerio: So finally, yeah, yeah,
sure. It's
Konrad: alright. Yeah, so your
background Carlini. So you said
you got into crypto 2013 started
mining on your gaming PC? What?
How old were you at the time?
2014.
Carlini8: If I had to guess it
was probably 2014 as was mining,
I was in that house 2013 2015.
And it was probably in the
middle of 2014. I was 24. It's
easier, just add 10 to the
whatever you were in.
Konrad: Alright, all right. And
like what background did you
have before that? Do you do you
have a college degree do you do
come from a technical
background?
Carlini8: So I went to I went to
uni and I did maths and biology.
After I graduated, I went to a
DNA testing company, using the
biology side of things for a few
years. But while I was there, I
started gambling in my spare
time, and it was gambling with
its it started off with
something called match betting
where you you kind of play the
odds. And no matter what
happens, you make a profit you
you bet on every outcome. And
you know, I talked about that
for hours but in a way I gambled
for a living in a way that is
mathematically viable. It wasn't
I wasn't a degen and I was I was
actually running a business. And
that got so big that I was
actually losing money going to
work. So I had to I had to say
to my boss I look I'm sorry,
I've got a quick I used I kept
getting like promoted and moved
up all right.
Konrad: But again, again, you
need to go more into detail. So
that was after after graduating
college uni and then working for
a DNA DNA company and then next
to that you start a gambling
match match betting what exactly
how does it work?
Carlini8: So, in I guess in a
quick rundown Is gambling
companies want you to gamble
with them, there's a lot of
competition to gamble. So they
want you to pick them over any
of their competitors. So they
give you an offer, hey, deposit
100 pounds, and we'll give you
100 pounds of fake money. And
you have to do a certain amount
of gambling until you can
withdraw any money. So I use the
math side of things to figure
out, right is this offer worth
doing. So I've put in 100
pounds, I now have 200 pounds,
but I have to gamble 2000
pounds. So I worked out if I
should, if I would make money
doing that. And normally, they
would make it profitable for
you. Because even without you
thinking about it, if you were
just gambling on random stuff,
they're making it so that you
should win originally, you get
hooked. And then eventually you
give it all back and more to
them. So that's their play. So
they, they effectively try and
make you win early. hook you in.
So horrible practice is really
destroyed some lives. But if you
just take the good part of that
offer, if you take the bit where
they're making it so that you
should win, and then leave and
then repeat with another company
and then repeat with another
company. And then you know, just
keep keep going. And that was
effectively where it all
started. And then that grew into
quite a big business. All right,
quit I quit my job in 2015 and
was a gambler until effectively
COVID.
Konrad: So karma really were you
making per month as a
professional gambler.
Carlini8: It did vary based on
the we're always December was
always a good month, because
companies would put out
effectively advent calendars
where every day, they would put
out an offer. And it was really
busy because he had to go
through all the sites and figure
out which company had actually
put out a good offer and which
one a terrible offer. Because
they weren't all just because
their offers didn't mean they
were worth doing. And also
throughout the time period. I
was I got progressively better
at it. But at the same time the
gambling companies made it
harder and harder. So it's like
an all way always a battle to
innovate and sort of move on. I
my peak, I was probably making
50,000 pounds a month
Konrad: how many dollars are
that? Approximately?
Carlini8: 70,000 pounds 65.
Almost exactly. 65. And that's
because that's gambling as well
in the UK gambling is tax free.
Which is a shame that crypto and
NFTs are classed as gambling
because I'll tell you if you're
listening Boris or Rishi, I am
gambling
Konrad: and how many hours a day
were we working on your gambling
Carlini8: It was quite it was
quite a lot it was. So I was in
business?
the mindset that I wouldn't get
another opportunity like this in
life and I really had to you
know, really grasp it while I
could. So I was I was working.
You know, most of the time
before I had kids, it was you
know the only other thing I
really did was spend time with
my wife and sometimes sometimes
go out and then when I had kids
I did it less because I spend
more time with them. That's
another good thing I was always
at home to to help out and see
them. But yeah, the mindset was
work all the time. But obviously
I had lazy periods. But I just
wanted to go for it while I
could. But slowly NFTs kind of
took over so I was I was
gambling during 2017 NFTs 2018
NFTs 2019 NFTs because the money
just wasn't really there. Like
the the NFT market you guys have
experienced I would have never
kept gambling. If that was what
it was like it was so bad that I
was making I was making money
gambling to put into NFTs
because I believed in NFTs but I
was not making money in NFTs
Konrad: I mean it makes sense
for you to squeeze out
everything you could but at what
point and how do you find about
crypto because if you're working
all the time, like how did you
find it?
Carlini8: I found it when I
found gambling ish when I found
match betting because I was
always you know, I don't even
really fully know how I found
match betting. So I did the
match betting concept on my own
just before I sort of found it I
did it. And I was like, this
should be a thing. So I kind of
went looking, found it. And at
the same time, people were using
Bitcoin to move money around. So
I'd done some research into
crypto. But the thing about
crypto then is you could only
really to make to make money two
or three ways you could trade.
And I was not a trader, and
trading takes losses to learn,
you could found and, you know, I
just found crypto, I couldn't
build something or raise any
money or do anything like that.
Or you could just hold it. And
that's just parking money. And
you're always just hoping it
goes up. Obviously, you can go
back in time, and no, it goes
up. But there wasn't any
opportunity like there is now
where you can take ethereum do
stuff with it and have more
Ethereum i That's generally what
people in the NFT space are
doing. They're trying to make
ETH, which you couldn't do back
then you couldn't I mean, some
people did. But it wasn't
common. So I always knew of
crypto when a couple of days ago
guess match betting groups where
they had like minded people. And
a couple of them were getting
into crypto. So I can't remember
there was some, some, I think,
weekly report that a couple of
friends had bought into that we
all spoke about every week that
sort of just kept our eye and
looking for possibilities.
Because we we were mainly
looking at it from a bitcoin
casino point of view, because if
they started putting good offers
on all you have to do is make a
bitcoin address, you know, it
was almost unlimited free money.
And unfortunately, they never
really, they never really
brought in big office.
Konrad: And you said that right
now someone can put eth to make
more eth. So how do you exactly
multiply is that you have? And
how much do you need to start
with? Because I think that's
also important question.
Carlini8: Well, it's really
easy, all you do is you mint one
bored ape for naught point
naught eight, if, then you just
hold it, you get you get a dog a
mutant, you know, that's fair to
say, if you go ape, it's, you
know, it's, it's the NFT Casino.
That's what people are doing.
And some people are very good at
it. And they're making a lot of
ETH. And some people are just
funding those people. But we do
have lots of injection of
Ethereum from people who truly
believe in what they're buying.
You have young people spending
hundreds of 1000s of ETH on
pieces that they truly believe
will be worth lots in 10 years
in 20 years. You know, when when
Gary Vee bought loads of punks
for a lot of ETH he's not
looking to flip, he hasn't sold
one, his his punks are sitting
there waiting for you know when
he's 80 and he can do something
with them. Whereas that Ethereum
he put in has gone to someone
else to then go back into the
casino. So these these people
are bringing in lots of Ethereum
that the true believers, I guess
that is just pumping up other
people's bags and letting people
then spend that Ethereum and
other projects and and pushing
it all up.
Konrad: Alright, and how do you
choose the project that you want
to flip? I mean, obviously, like
it can vary a lot of things like
hype and Tim, etc. But if
someone's looking to Soulages
make a lot of money quickly.
What is your criteria?
Carlini8: Well, right now,
you've I guess you've got a
feel, feel the hype that certain
projects have for the shore
things. For example, I can't
remember what is called Moon
Moon owls. The Kevin Rose one I
think is minting a 2.5 Ethereum.
And that certainly, that
certainly doesn't seem like it
will be a bad buy. But getting
onto that whitelist is hard
because everyone thinks it's
free Ethereum that sort of
thing. Has a solid team behind
it that have delivered multiple
things in their life. And I'm
sure that project will do well.
Whereas on the flip side, you
have a similar hype level for
things like pick someone. And
that was purely marketing. There
was there was no team behind it.
There was That was just a
roulette spin. But people
effectively got wrong. But some
people actually did flip and
revealed before it was seen what
the art looked like. But if more
if you're telling people like
how to make money, it needs to
be the solid projects. And if
you just, if you just know you
want to degen, I guess if you
know that, there's that
possibility to lose, then what
you have to do is, secure your
profits when you can. And the
hard bit is looking back, I have
owned many apes that I've sold.
And I sold them at five ETH, 10
ETH 15 ETH. And I, if you look
back at those, you know, it
haunts you, I owned over 100
punks. And I sold them all, you
know before, before they breach
10. And then obviously, they
went over 100. There is no one
that has perfectly traded any
NFT. So you just have to accept
that you won't be perfect. And
you're you will if you just if
you go pure degen, and you're
gonna hold bags. But also you
will get out of winners too
early. There's there's just no
two ways about it. I think
mindset is a big thing here.
Konrad: All right. Why did you
say earlier that a mint price of
2.5 is doesn't sound like a bad
buy.
Carlini8: Because of the project
itself, let me try and I can't
fully it's moon birds XYZ. So is
by is by Kevin Rose. And the
they founded proof. XYZ, which I
last time I checked that the
floor for that was 80 Ethereum.
So there's there's a lot of hype
going into it because of what
they've already done. Kevin Rose
has done a hell of a lot in his
life. And his is co founder I
can't remember what his name is.
Ken just trying to have a quick
scroll to for remember, I've
listened to their spaces, but I
can't remember his name. They've
both done a lot of big deals and
like they could be retired if
they wanted to be there. I think
it's a good if you have the
opportunity, I think that should
be bought because it very much
feels like with the experience
the team have the hype around
the project and their ability
2.5 ETH won't be where it stops
just comparing it to the other
projects on the market at the
moment.
Konrad: Yep. All right. If
you're if you're comparing the
NFT let's say the NFT casino to
what you did back back almost 10
years ago, right? The gambling
business. It was matched betting
right. Match betting means
you're betting on a match. It's
a football match, or how do I
understand?
Carlini8: Well, just like in, in
the simplest terms, a match bet
would be betting on every
outcome. So it doesn't have to
be football. But if you're
betting on football, you could
bet on win draw and loss. But
you you bet on a win with
whatever company you've just
signed up to, which then will
allow you to get a free bet from
them. So they'll give you a fake
100 pounds, which you can then
use later on a second bet. And
then you lay the bet somewhere
like Betfair where and a lay
just means not so you would bet
on not win with Betfair and you
bet on a win with whatever
company it is, but you can also
you can bet on tennis is quite a
common one. You know, there are
only two outcomes there. Even
even horse racing, you know
people people did it on the
Grand National just the other
day because you could if you
cover every horse are using
these this free money that they
give you, you then have quite
the result at the end although
after about a year or so I moved
away from match betting and it
was actually the casino side of
things. But it was in a match
betting way. I guess running it.
The maths was on my side, but
you could go on bad losing runs.
Konrad: All right. And you
started math right. So I guess
that helped you with the
probability calculations right?
Carlini8: A bit, but the word
calculators so it's not like I
was doing stuff on the fly in my
head. I was more just keying
stuff into spreadsheets, but
just understanding how it
worked. Quite a lot of people
who made a lot of money doing
this. Had no idea about the
mouse. And they quite often
would get scared after a few
months of losing.
Konrad: Alright, interesting.
But it's still fair to say that
you were some kind of genius,
right? I mean, I mean, you still
are right, but not now. You're a
NFT. Genius.
Carlini8: You can't You're not
allowed to say that yourself.
Well, no, it's not. I'm not
even. I'm not book smarts. I'm
just, I guess, internet smarts.
I know. I know, my way around
the internet. Now is what
Konrad: did you did you watch
the Netflix movie? There was
like a Netflix movie where there
was like a guy from College,
where he was in like, a US
college and went to the math
class. And he was like, super
good. And then the teacher.
Like, one, yeah. 21. And yeah,
and they they played blackjack
and stuff. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
that was super, super inspiring.
They made tons of money and
lost. And lost it. Oh, by the
way, how did your your boss
react? When you when you went to
him and told them now? Well,
Carlini8: I, I, I walked up to
her. And I said, Can I can I
have a word? And her reply was,
Oh, good. You don't have a
letter. Because she was she was
a client. So she knew how much I
was making at the time. So like,
it wasn't a secret in the office
or anything like that. And my
reply to her was, oh, I need a
letter do I? She was so went to
the meeting room. And yes, she
just, she knew it was coming and
said something along the lines
of, there's no amount of money I
can offer you to keep you as the
as I said, not within your
budget. We are still friends, I
still went early 2015. So we're
coming up to seven years. And
you know, I've, I've had a meal
with it this year. A couple of
old work friends I still meet up
with
Konrad: All right, so I mean, my
original question was, if you
compare the NFT, casino to the,
to the gambling business you
did, where do you see
connections? What did you learn?
What learnings have you done
previously, with your gambling
business? You know, maybe
controlling your emotions,
focusing on on demand for the
right rational thinking and
stuff? What learnings did you
make from your previous
experience that you think, or
that you can share with the
community that is interested in
let's say, the NFT. Casino?
Carlini8: It was it was mindset,
really. Because gambling before
was very mathematical. I knew
that if I kept going, I should
make money. It didn't mean that
I would. Because when you're
I can see quite easily an NFT
being worth, you know, a floor
doing things like to maximize
Evie, you take the whole amount
of money. So say I deposited 200
pounds, and I got a 200 pound
bonus, I'd put all 400 pounds on
one number on roulette, purely
because that was mathematically
the best way to do it. So when
you're just throwing away for
throwing away money until you
hit because there are 37 slots
on a roulette wheel. So in
theory, I should hit one in 37.
You know, that takes a toll on
you if if you just have a bad
day, and it's very possible to
go 100 without hitting. And
you're just like, oh my god, a
terrible day, you just always
think if I'd literally done
nothing today, if I stayed in
bed, I'd be so much richer than
I was than I am now. So what a
waste of my time I've spent my
time and my effort and I'm down.
And I've done exactly what I
should. Now you can't do that in
the NFT world because buying
something and expecting it to go
up isn't maths, it's not a
formula. It's not set in stone,
what should happen. It's more
feeling. But what you can do is
you can be in the right mindset
when Cryptos dumping like it is
now to just take a step back and
really look is this is crypto a
thing? Are we actually going to
still be here in 10 years? And
yes, I very, I very much think
it's a certainty at this point.
And I think NFTs are in that
space. So if you can handle the
ups and the downs of these main
projects that have teams that
are staying, that are doing
things that are going to be
impactful in a few years. If you
of 1000 Ethereum. Very long
term. I can't tell you what one
have the conviction like The
people I've known who have made
the most in NFT, since 2017, are
those that have gone for a
project and made insane bets on
them. So I know Pranksy very
well I got Pranksy into the
space. I, I, you know, was in a
slack with Pranksy, pre crypto
kitties in 2017. And pranksy, he
had 1250 bored ape or one point
and sold most of them on the way
up made, Mises made millions of
pounds and is credited for
effectively, very carefully
selling them and helping not
crushed the community. Because
if it Pranksy just be like,
right, let's list them all. One
if you know, that wall just is
never getting crossed. I don't
think bored apes make it because
the community wouldn't be as
feel good as it was. Because the
community is strong. But it was
weaker back then obviously, and
the growth helped strengthen
them. And on the flip side, I've
also friends with Jimmy Dot eth,
who held a couple of hundreds,
at the same time and sold less
and still has maybe 80. And his
conviction just led to you know,
we're talking it's a bit crazy
here because we're talking
retired for the rest of your
life with an insane budget. And
the difference between retired
for the rest of your life and
then same budget and a couple of
yachts. So you know, it's it's a
ridiculous gap. But it's also
the minimum we're talking about
is already huge. So the big
winners, when you look back are
always those who buy into
projects that they believe in
and stick with them. You know,
cocoa bear is someone else. Snow
fro I tried to get him to sell a
zombie crypto punks, zombie for
fingers 40 Ethereum, when
Ethereum was maybe $800, it was
something like that. And I was
like, Look, you need to sell
you've got 30 of them. And he
was going to spend it on real
estate which eventually ended up
being a staging place for our
block. So I think he's still
happy with the sale because of
where it led. But he had so many
posts. So many zombie punks. And
it was so hard for me to
convince him to sell one further
time the highest sale ever, that
these people just have the
conviction and they stick to it
and they make lots of money. I
can't tell anyone if that sort
of time period is over.
that's going to be obviously
apes are currently leading the
charge and they're your safest
bet. But is that how you make
lots of money now? I'm I'm not
sure. All right.
Valerio: All right. By the way,
talking about apes, I heard that
that you thought that the launch
of the ape token that you didn't
think you made a good job on
that. Am I right?
Carlini8: I don't like that the
apes don't yield the token. Yes,
I think we're releasing our own
token for Purrnelope's Country
Club. And I think about token
hours a day. And I have maybe
four months at this point, maybe
even five or six. And I much
prefer an NFT. That yields a
token. Because you're adding
value to the NFT. At this point,
apes have two things. They have
the ape token, and they have the
NFT. And in my mind, the token
is taking away value from the NF
T but the question here is, can
they use the funds they raised
from the token to offset that
loss for apes. And for them?
They probably can be they can
use the funds to build enough
for apes. But I don't think
anyone else can. So if anyone
copies them. That's a problem.
And historically, everyone
copies apes like there's just no
two ways about it. Someone will
try and copy them and they won't
launch on every exchange at the
same time the first token ever
to do that. They won't have
these these backings providing
the liquidity early on or have
the funds to do that and They
will just take their whole
projects with a token that
ultimately people don't want.
For instance, board apes had
some launched ape with utility,
that just doesn't work for any
other projects that you need
utility out the gate, or it's
not going to work. Or it's an
uphill battle, I guess at that
point, it's much easier to
launch with utility than to
launch without it and then try
and capture it
Konrad: just allows you launch
your own token right now won't
be like the exact steps you will
take and what will be the
utility for the token itself.
Carlini8: Wonderful. First step
is to do it legally. So I can't
launch it in the UK. So the
token is going to be launched in
the British Virgin Isles, there
is a company already set up.
Just paid for within arm's
reach. When did this the 15th of
December, it was launched that
just shows how far back we were
thinking about it. So we can
legally launch the token, most
tokens aren't launched legally.
And I think that will be a big
problem for projects as well,
because like I've said earlier,
the team is the important bit
when teams are covered. If
you're successful, you bring
more light onto your projects.
And when it's eventually found
out that a token wasn't launched
legally and the team is pursued,
you know, they might abandon the
project, or they might go to
prison, they're not going to
keep working on on this
illegally launch token now. So
step one is to launch it
legally, which is all sorts of
and step two is to provide the
utility. So what what I've done
is I've looked at a lot of other
projects that have done similar
things. So Cyberkongz, for
example, have a yielding token,
and it was very successful with
them, breeding babies sup ducks
had volt. And that went well
with the snack shop that they
had. So we'll be launching our
tier twos, which is effectively
our, our mutants or our meebit,
you know, that sort of level of
the community. And that will be
purely, it will be purely in
token. So you can only receive
that with token. So people will
be using it to gain that long
term will want it in our NFT
world.
Konrad: James James, can you
quickly clarify what you mean
exactly by a yield token?
Carlini8: So just normally,
every day, you get a little
trickle of the token. So it
builds up over time,
effectively.
Valerio: So instead of instead
of getting hammered, how much do
they get, like 20 20,000 Apes
per per bored ape, right? So
instead of getting all 20,000,
you should get them like on a on
a schedule, right? Like, daily
or something?
Carlini8: Yes, it's slowly
slowly release it. Because if
you have all of the tokens,
you're going to get up front,
they did, you know, they sent a
lot to the DAO and the DAO is
voting on some sort of token
yielding. But they're, they're
doing it where you lock up, ape
to get it and the NFT counts as
a key. It's it's a little tricky
to talk about now because
something was proposed. And then
the apes voted it down. And now
something new is being proposed.
And we're not sure if it's
actually going to happen yet. So
we don't actually know how
they're doing it. But they're
like their AirDrop, for example.
Wasn't that much. wasn't a big
percentage. I don't have the
figures in front of me right
now. But it was it was maybe 20%
was the airdrop 40% was the DAO
and then the rest went to Yuga,
the charity partners and the
team I think
Konrad: one more thing I would
like to touch on aside from
token is a team which mentioned
a lot during this episode. So
how to build a really good team
that will stay with you for a
long time. And I second question
will be how much money do you
need upfront? Because no one
really talks about salaries for
teams. So like, if you'd like to
start your own project, how much
would you need to pay them on a
monthly basis?
Carlini8: Well, that's that's
tricky because when you start
bringing in this in this sort of
space, people can be from
anywhere, right? You don't, you
don't have to hire around you,
you don't have to hire in the
US. You know, even like, none of
the Purrnelope's team, there
isn't an office, we don't meet
up everyone's remote. So the
team could in theory be from
anywhere. And what you need to
do is you need to make sure you
get the right people in the
right places, but that doesn't.
That's more about their skills.
So you need your community
manager to have web 3
experience, for example, you
need your community manager to
know about NF Ts, because that's
who they interact with, you
can't have them looking like a
complete noob in front of your
community. Whereas say, your
website dev doesn't need to,
they can just be a really good
website dev from web two. So
there are certain roles where
you can pull in web two, and
you really need web three. And
there are some that you can kind
of cross over, for example,
marketing, you, you probably
need at least one person in your
marketing team who knows about
web three and is experienced in
it. But a really good marketer
from web 2 world or just you
know, anywhere can then come in
and bring ideas to help grow
your project that way. Salary
wise, it's you, you want to pay
people well, you'll be looking
at high end pay. certain roles
are very tricky to get. Now you
can even a solidity Dev, what
you can do is find a dev in web
two, to learn solidity because
depending on your projects, they
there's there's a lot they can
look at. So if you're just doing
a 10k PFP, for example, they can
look at our project or apes or
doodles and look at their
contract because it's all open
source, and see how to do it
themselves. And then after
enough time, they become you
know, if you've got someone who
really wants to better
themselves, they can then learn
enough over that time. Because
in reality, there aren't really,
you know, the best Ethereum devs
haven't been doing it 10 years
because Ethereum isn't 10 years
old. It's more about how quickly
people learn and how willing
they are to learn.
Valerio: And it's cheaper like
that, right? It's cheaper,
getting a web 2 dev, learn
solidity instead of hiring a web
three dev,
Carlini8: it's also easier,
yeah, because there are more of
them than there are that already
know solidity. And the issue
with solidity. devs is they know
how much is going to how much
your NFTs are going to sell for.
And that then makes it quite
tricky. Especially if you're
mainly putting back into the
community. So like, I think we
sold out for $3 million, I think
it was when you at the time and
you know, multiply it all out
the 800. If we took in that, you
know, maybe 10% of that has gone
on salary, it's without No,
probably it will be more than
10% Just you know, thinking
about it quickly for a second.
But it's not a huge chunk. Most
of it has gone back in and none
of it has gone into anyone's
pocket. So you need a team that
will understand it is a company.
And most you know web two people
coming into web three would see
it as that. Whereas if someone's
been in NFTs quite a long time,
they might have seen you know
pudgy penguins, they minted out
and sent all the Ethereum to
their own private wallets. Which
was a bit crazy at the time. And
for me, that's that's a bit of a
red flag and they went on to
then sell the project someone
else a few days ago. So fine,
finding a team is hard. you're
best off building friends first
building a friendship group
thinking who's in, you know who
actually wants to be in this
what their skills, place them in
the right place, and then go and
find what you don't have the
will you'll never be able to get
a group of friends that have
everything. Bored apes, for
example, went and found the
artists they didn't even have
the ability to create this art
that has become so monumental.
They hired in three or four
artists for that. So you just
got to play to your strengths
and find what you can in reality
to find you can either change
your name on Twitter to is
hiring, I see that a lot. So I
assume it works. That's not what
I did. Or discord, we found
website 2.0 People just because
in one of the channels, one of
the discourse has a NFT Bill
doors channel, and they just
posted, hey, we were web devs
just looking to do some things.
And I contacted them. And that's
sort of how that connection was
made. So it's just been active,
sort of living and breathing.
The project, I guess, alright,
Valerio: can you still do that
now? Or, or what what would now
be the best and most efficient
way to find dev to find artists
to find different people for
your team?
Carlini8: If you're looking to
launch soon, and you've already
got, you know, a couple of
crypto NFT friends, for artists,
honestly, I'd go to Instagram,
you know, it's I'd scroll
Instagram, I'd put in some kind
of art hashtag. I'd scroll until
I find some art that looks
great. And I'd I'd message maybe
20 People have great looking at
have some sort of pitch message
that's like, Hey, we're looking
to build this. We were looking
for an artist we'd like to what
I'd say to them is that we're
looking to have someone
involved, we want an artist who
will continue to work on this,
you'll probably be skeptical of
NFTs because everyone outside of
NFTs hates NFTs is pretty much
how it goes. So I would, I would
say look, I'm willing to listen
to all your concerns, artists
will probably have the two main
concerns of selling stolen art,
which is better than the real
world, which is very annoying,
because you only know the art is
getting sold because of the NFT.
And it's not most NFTs and it's
no successful NFTs. And the
environment, which you can then
talk about the merge is coming
and that will make Ethereum so
much better better than paying
on a canvas and shipping it
across the world. And then get
them involved. Have them as a co
founder Don't say, I mean, if
you want to make as much money
as possible, what you do is you
you basically screw over the
artist and you say yeah, we'll
do it for we'll do a fixed fee,
and you do that. But my artist
is Apollo have more now. But at
the time I said look full time
job salary. Come on in both,
there was no sort of percentages
because we're not splitting it.
We weren't minting and then
splitting the cash. But if you
just say, look, you're a co
founder you're in. Eventually
you'd find it artists that way
is I think, all right,
Konrad: cool. How did you pay
your artists a salary if you
didn't launch your project that
just with your own money? Or
Carlini8: yeah, so I, I said to
these two guys, that I'd fund it
for a year already. Because, you
know, as in NFTs and NFTs have
gone crazy. And it's so quite a
few and I had money set aside.
So I put some money aside, and
in my head that was for this
project. And when that run run
out, you know, it was over, I
guess. So this was this was a
bet on the project working? And
if the money if the money ran
out that was that, I guess.
Konrad: All right. Well, if you
take someone on the percentage,
then you may you're like sure
that they will be very involved
in that they believe in the
project itself. And I'm
committed.
Carlini8: Yeah, and artists who
will be working on it more than
right, can you make this 10k
PFP. For me, and then when it's
done, that's done. But if the
artist is in, they could make
the 10k PFP. And then they could
start work on some marketing
materials, go on Twitter, and
then they can start working on
your secondary products or just,
you know, fun stuff where your
your profile picture project is
in a scene and build up the law
because they truly believe in
the project because that in the
projects is it's just a lot
better that way.
Konrad: All right. So I'm trying
to recap for our listeners. So
to find an artist, you suggest
going to Instagram and then
search for a specific hashtag.
Do you maybe have a short
example of a hash tag?
Carlini8: Well, it depends what
you're you're going for. I was
looking for a H fans and artists
this way not not for our project
but for something specific
within the project. And I think
it was building art because I
was looking for sort of
landscape and that sort of
thread. So every you know, like
if you're if you're doing a seal
project You know, try just
hashtag art and look at the
reasons, but maybe CLR, PT or
animal art, or I don't know if
those hashtags are real, you
know, just just get a bit
creative around what you're
looking at, for the artists to
do. All right, and you should be
able to find it.
Konrad: Like just a quick tip,
if you if you want one profile,
you can just press the arrow
button next to the Follow
button, and it will have a drop
down of similar profiles. So
like, you will have suggested
similar ones. Smart move, Konrad
Carlini8: did not know that. I
live in Instagram noob.
Valerio: All right, and then
have you your pitch message
ready and send them a nice pitch
and stuff. What about devs
though? I mean, I assume web
three depths or like the, like
the web three job with the
highest demand, but the low
supply? Am I right?
Carlini8: It's very much seems
that way. I've seen a couple
people claiming on Twitter that
it's good community managers are
really? And I guess that's,
that's hard to quantify, because
they're very much saying good.
So, you know, what does? What
does that mean? You know, people
will have fun. Yeah, exactly.
Valerio: So if you had to go and
find, like, one, a web three dev
right now and a community
manager now, what would you do
it? And? And yeah,
Carlini8: I think I would try
and pull a community manager
from a community I was already
in. So an active discord that
I'm in, I would try looking for.
I think I just already know, by
being in the, in the discords. A
couple of people who I think
have the potential to do the job
well. And I'd I'd I'd kind of
rank them and speak to them in
that order, I guess. Dev YT Dev.
I, I just I just knew one.
That's it. That's my problem. I
I knew a dev who I think I was
in a discord with them. And I
was saying like, I'm trying to
find a web 3 Dev, it's really
hard, not sort of fishing, but
just sort of in general. And
they were like, I could try it.
I was like, Okay, you think so?
So yeah, it would be hard. I'll
just read some contracts and go
from there. And they basically
just read loads of contracts and
got used to the language and
figured it all out.
Konrad: We have two tabs. But I
guess like, GitHub is big for
for devs. write or read it and
because I heard some people just
you know, post on Reddit or go
to communities on Reddit. And
that's but yeah. And if you
know, a specific thing you would
do right now to get the depth.
You can tell it if not.
Carlini8: I'd asked my dad if he
knew any devs, because he's a
dev. B, and here's the issue is
he's not really motivated by
money. He's motivated by
enjoying his job. So maybe I
could convince him to do it.
Such that he just doesn't care
about NFTs enough. But I could
ask him to find me a dev from
work or something like that, or
from a past job. Who's a good
Dev, you know? And so obviously,
that doesn't, if your listeners
want to call my dad his numbers,
oh seven.
Konrad: Because when you said
that you need a web 2 dev and to
learn like to make him learn
solidity. It sounds like super
hard task. Because what do you
say like you approach him and
say, Hey, I'm gonna build this
project, I need you for it.
Like, all you have to do is
learn solidity and that's it.
It's possible.
Carlini8: To us it sounds really
hard. But from from the devs
have spoken to that have learned
it, they've said it's not too
tricky. Like if, if they're
generally a good Dev, I think
they should be able to make the
basic leap that you need to
launch a project, they should be
able to do that quite easily. If
you're there
Konrad: well, it's it's smiley,
or is it dimension division,
Carlini8: everyone will be
different, but over the same way
as the artists that try and get
them properly in, you know, to
to join your vision. You're
going to need a reason for this
project. Like what are you doing
differently that is going to you
know, why? Why why are people
going to care about your
project, you need to convince
them that you can actually mint
out and get the funds to make
this into a proper job.
Valerio: All right, cool. I see.
Thank you. Carlini. I think that
was some some fire advice for
are all our listeners very, very
valuable? The last thing before
we let you go? It's something I
always love to talk about. What
Why do you like? I mean, you
talked about Bitcoin first,
right? And how you like it? How
we prefer a few than Bitcoin
because you can build
applications or you can build
stuff on Ethereum. But how
what's what's your point of view
on the topic of
decentralization? Because that's
something that I am concerned.
And that's also what I focus a
lot. And decentralization is
important for me, right? And
bitcoin is just way more
decentralized than Ethereum, for
example, so that's why I'm a
little bit I mean, of course,
Ethereum 2.0 is coming out and
the merge will be great. And,
and but how do you see the point
of decentralization that if
you're young guys, the boys from
the foundation are holding
almost 70% of the tokens and
stuff? And, I mean, we just went
from proof of work to proof of
stake right? Like that,
Carlini8: to me, it's a level of
scale. Like decentralization
isn't yes or no. Like. Bitcoin
is more decentralized, but it
isn't completely decentralized
because someone can set up it's
just a matter of tech right? If
you have enough mining power, it
Bitcoin isn't decentralized,
because you have enough to 51%
attack or whatever. It's just a
different level to Ethereum it
is more decentralized. But for
me, I'm not personally too
worried because it is Ethereum
is far more decentralized than
Solana what we already have,
yeah. Well, Solana is just a
Google spreadsheet in my mind.
So it's, it's about as
decentralized as the, you know,
my my organizational
spreadsheets? Unless Sam you're
listening and you want to invest
in PCC, then it's the most
decentralized token in the world
is the best and I love it. If
you're not it's No, I, you know,
I'm very surface level on Solana
and the surface level seems to
be it turns off all the time,
and it runs on about four PCs.
But for me, Ethereum is
decentralized enough. And I
guess what I care about more is
the stuff on it. So you can read
everything is open source? Well,
most things that people interact
with are open source, and they
can be checked. And you have
people like quit going through
contracts, when they're launched
and telling everyone what's in
them. And it's, it's that level
of openness, that is more
important to me, because that
will matter. To the users like
what we're doing is changing
everyday life in a more simple
way. Whereas Bitcoin, I guess,
you could argue, will have a
huge effect, because it depends
how, you know, doom and gloom,
er, and the whole economy of the
world. But if you're not on that
side of the scale, if if that
isn't a huge worry for you,
which you know, people like you,
it should be your main worry.
For me, you know, personally, I
don't think it will get there,
I'm sure you know, will be sent
laser links and do your own
research and all this stuff
about how I should have hundreds
of Bitcoin because the world's
going going to hell. But I guess
living in my nicer, happier
bubble, of where, where we don't
think governments are trying to
kill us off in a great reset.
The fact is, we can't scam each
other as easily on Ethereum in
more everyday life. So Ethereum
is more decentralized than what
we have now. So it is better.
And I It doesn't matter to me
that there's something even more
decentralized because you can't
do stuff with it, I guess.
Valerio: All right. All right. I
mean, I think it's big on film.
They have two different use
cases. I mean, exactly. Yeah.
Carlini8: They don't they're not
competing in any way.
Valerio: Exactly. We cannot put
them we cannot compare them and
try to make them compete each
other. I mean,
Carlini8: coingecko and that's
about it.
Valerio: Exactly. All right.
Yeah. Cool. Thank you so much,
Konrad. Do you have any
questions?
Konrad: Still, now I've asked
all the ones to ask. So yeah,
thank you very much Carlini for
joining us today. It was a
pleasure talking to
Carlini8: No problem. Thanks for
having me on.
Konrad: It was an amazing
podcast man. It was super super
insightful and valuable and I'm
sure the community can can learn
a lot from from what you share.